Lonely.
‫وحيدة‬
Why did you sigh?
لماذا تتنهدين
I feel a bit lonely too.
أنا أيضًا
You have a boyfriend.
لديك حبيب
You shouldn't feel lonely.
ما زلت وحيدا
I find it strange as well.
أنا أيضاً أشعر بالغرابة
Actually,
في الواقع
before I knew how he felt about me,
لم أكن أعرف مشاعره
I felt fulfilled every day.
‫أشعر بالراحة كل يوم‬
I was always guessing
أفكر كل يوم
what his movements and expressions meant.
‫ما معنى‬
My mood swung up and down
كل يوم
like a roller coaster.
مثل ركوب قطار الموت
He's my boyfriend now,
الآن تبدأ في حب
but I feel
أشعر
he's not that good,
أنه ليس جيدًا جدًا
even a bit childish.
حتى أنه ساذج قليلا
Anyway, I feel
على أي حال أشعر
he's not as good as I thought.
أنه ليس جيدا كما ظننت
I don't know.
لا أعرف
What do you think, Grandma?
ما رأيك يا جدتي
What is a roller coaster?
‫ما هي قطار الموت‬
Forget it.
انسي الأمر
Are you done washing dishes?
هل انتهيت؟
Go back and roast some potatoes for me if you're done.
‫بعد غسلك عد وأطبخ بعض البطاطس‬
But we've just finished dinner.
لقد تناولت العشاء للتو
A well-fed person can't understand hunger.
‫الرجل الشهي لا يعرف الجوع
Who did it?
من
Batay.
با تاي
Bakhetbek!
‫باري فيكت
You stepped on sheep dung again?
لقد دست على phân الخروف مرة أخرى
Did you do this?
هل فعلت ذلك؟
You tied my shoelaces together
ربط ربط حذائي معًا
and made me fall.
وسقطت
What makes you think I did it?
لماذا تقول أنني فعلت ذلك؟
How do you know?
كيف عرفت
This is a shepherd's knot, a shepherd's knot!
هذا عقد الرعاية عقدة الرعاية
Who else could be so obnoxious?
‫باستثنائك من سيكون بهذا السوء‬
People riding horses all know this kind of knot.
كل من يركب الخيل يمكنه ربطه
I didn't tie this knot,
على الرغم من أنني لم أربطه
but I can untie it for you.
لكن دعيني أساعدك
Watch and learn.
تتعلم
What happened to your face?
ما خطب وجهك؟
Mohebit beat me yesterday.
لقد ضربني ماو هي بيي أمس
Later,
بعد قليل
let me take you somewhere.
سآخذك إلى مكان
I have things to do.
أنا مشغول
I'm going back to the pine forest.
سأعود إلى سونغلين
Come on.
اذهب
I'll show you something great.
سآخذك لرؤية شيء جيد
What's it?
أي شيء جيد
Something great.
إنه شيء جيد
Lift your leg.
ساقك، ساقك ترتجف
One, two, here you go.
واحد اثنان هيا
Why are we here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Come.
لنذهب
Let me show you something.
سآخذك لرؤية شيء
I have things to do.
أنا مشغول
You've run out of paper, right?
ليس لديك ورق
Birch bark contains a lot of oil.
‫زيت الشجرة عالية‬
You can fold it as you please
قومي بتقطيعها
without breaking it.
لا مشكلة
Many people write on it.
كثير من الناس يستخدمون هذه الكتابة
You don't have to fight with Yerdana for exercise books.
لا داعي أن تتنازع كتاب الواجبات مع ييدا
You heard it?
هل سمعت؟
Yeah.
سمعت
I saw it too.
لقد رأيت أيضا
You're very popular.
أنت مشهور جدا
What do you mean?
ماذا؟
The Daur guy from Tacheng,
إنه من قرية داكار من تا تشينج
he likes you too, doesn't he?
إنه يحبك أيضا
We just exchanged a few words.
فقط قال بضع كلمات
It's not surprising that he likes you.
من الطبيعي أن يحبك
I like you too.
لأنني أحبك أيضا
I know how good you are.
أعلم أنك جيد
Do you like me?
هل تحبني؟
But
لكن
if I can't live the life you want with you,
إذا لم أستطع أن أعيش حياتك المفضلة معك
will you still like me?
هل ما زلت تحبني؟
The life I want?
الحياة التي أحبها
You want to be a writer
أنتِ تريدين أن تكوني كاتبة
and go to Beijing.
تريدين الذهاب إلى بكين
You want a life like that.
للعيش بهذه الحياة
I don't think I can go to Beijing.
أعتقد أنني لا أستطيع الذهاب إلى بكين
If we…
إذا نحن
If I can't go with you,
إذا لم أستطع الذهاب
can we still be together?
هل يمكننا أن نكون معا
If
إذا
I don't go, will you still like me?
إذا لم أذهب هل ما زلت تحبني
Your dad is against it, isn't he?
والدك لا يوافق
Yes.
لا يوافق
He doesn't approve of us being together.
هو لا يوافق على علاقتنا
He doesn't approve of me working in the stable.
لم يوافق على العمل في ساحة الخيل
Do you have to go back to the stable?
هل يجب عليك العودة إلى ساحة الخيل؟
I want to go back.
بالطبع أريد العودة إلى ساحة الخيل
That's the life I want.
هذا ما أريد أن أعيش فيه
I thought
كنت أفكر
after Yerdana grew up,
بعد أن تكبر ييدا
he could graze the herds with Dad.
يمكنني مرافقة أبي
But Tokan has gotten remarried.
لكن الآن توسل الزواج
If she takes her children with her,
إذا أخذنا الطفل
no one will be left to graze the herds.
لا يوجد أحد في المنزل
So I have to
يمكنني فقط
stay.
أبقى
Wenxiu.
"ون سيو".
I don't know what to do.
لا أعرف ماذا أفعل
I can stay on the ranch.
يمكنني البقاء في المزرعة
You're not going to Beijing?
ألن تذهب إلى بكين
I've got over that idea.
هذا ما كنت أفكر به من قبل
I thought
كنت أظن
I must go to Beijing to be a good writer.
يجب أن أذهب إلى بكين لكتابة مقالة جيدة
But now I feel
لكن الآن أشعر
there are many things I want to write about,
هناك الكثير من الأشياء التي أريد كتابتها
and I'm better at writing than before.
كتبت أفضل من ذي قبل
Yesterday, I thought
اعتقدت بالأمس
I couldn't write without paper.
لا يمكن كتابة المقال بدون ورق
But I have birch bark now.
‫لكن الآن يوجد جلد الشجرة‬
We're only 20 years old.
نحن في العشرين سنة فقط
I don't even know
لا أعرف
what kind of life I really like.
ما هي الحياة التي أحبها حقًا
Batay.
با تاي
I like this place,
أحب هذا المكان
not just because of you
ليس بسببك فقط
but also for myself.
بل من أجل نفسي
So why don't I stay and give it a try?
لماذا لا أحاول البقاء
Are you really going to stay on the ranch?
هل أنت متأكد من البقاء في المزرعة
Let's be together.
لنجرب
Okay.
حسنا
Sorry.
آسف
You look very happy.
أنت سعيد جدا
Are you dating someone?
‫التقاطع‬
Are you in a relationship?
الوقوع في الحب
Are you done?
انتهيت
Let's go.
لنذهب
I need to talk to you about something.
أريد مناقشة شيء معك
Can you not get in the way
هل يمكنك ألا توقفني
of me dating your mom?
أنا ووالدتك في الحب
You can date someone.
يمكنك الوقوع في الحب
Why can't I date your mom?
لماذا لا يمكنني الوقوع في الحب مع والدتك
I really like her.
أنا حقا أحبها
We want to start a family.
‫نريد أن نؤسس عائلة‬
What's wrong with me living with her?
هل هناك مشكلة في العيش معا
That's different.
هذا ليس نفس الشيء
How is it different?
‫ما هو الشيء نفسه‬
You're in love.
أنت تقع في الحب
We're in love too.
نحن الاثنان نحب بعضنا البعض
How is that different?
هذا ليس نفس الشيء
We're all just in love.
نحن في علاقة
If you're worried that I won't treat your mom well,
إذا كنت تخشى أن أعامل أمك بشكل سيء
you can tell me. I'll…
أخبريني أنا
Hurry up.
بسرعة
I can prove…
سأصنع لك
You're done?
انتهيت
I didn't know collecting wood ears was so tiring.
من يدري أن الأمر متعب للغاية
It's just a small business.
تجارة صغيرة
Don't expect to make a fortune from it.
هل تعتمد على الثروة الكبيرة
I wasn't expecting a fortune.
لم أفكر في الثروة الكبيرة
I was expecting you.
أتيت من أجل لقاء الجمال
I suddenly can't understand Kazakh.
لا أفهم الهاتف فجأة
You used to understand it?
‫لقد فهمت من قبل‬
Yes.
نعم
You don't believe me?
ألا تصدقني؟
I do.
لا
As long as you stay at a place for long enough
طالما أنك تبقى هنا لفترة كافية
and know the environment and people's relationships,
‫أنت تعرف بيئتهم وبينهم‬
you can guess what's going on
بالنظر إلى تعابيرهم
by looking at their expressions.
يمكن أن يخمن تقريبا
But this afternoon,
لكن بعد ظهر اليوم
when I was making soaps at the village chief's house,
كنت في منزل المدير
I suddenly couldn't understand anything.
لا أفهم أي شيء فجأة
I didn't know what they were talking about in Kazakh.
لا أعرف ماذا يقولون
Sulitan was angry with me,
لماذا غضب سو لي تان علي
but I didn't even know why.
لا أعرف
I'm thinking
أنا أفكر
maybe I'm really different from them.
أنا مختلف عنهم
You're indeed different from them.
أنت مختلف عنهم في الأصل
Why don't you leave with me in a while?
ما رأيك أن تذهب معي بعد فترة
Where should we go?
إلى أين؟
Think about it.
انظر
We're not locals.
جئنا نحن من الخارج
Neither are we herders.
لسنا موظفين
How long do you think
قل لي
we can live like this?
كم من الوقت يمكن أن تبقى مثل هذه الحياة
Am I right?
أليس كذلك؟
Either you'll go to Guangdong with me,
إما أن تذهب معي إلى جوانج دونج
or we'll go back to your hometown.
أو أعود إليك
We can collect some money and start a business.
وأحضر بعض المال للقيام بأعمال تجارية
Isn't that great?
هل تشعرين بعدم الراحة
Besides,
وفكري في النقطة الأخرى
Grandma is old,
جدتي كبيرة في السن
isn't she?
أليس كذلك
To be frank,
قل شيئًا سيئًا
if she falls ill one day,
ماذا لو أصبت بالمرض يوما ما
it'll be easier to find a doctor for her
هل من السهل
in a big city, right?
هل هذا مريح
What about Wenxiu?
أين ون شيو؟
Wenxiu?
ون شيو
Every bird has to leave the nest.
في العالم
Right?
أليس كذلك
That's a Cantonese saying.
لقد قلنا لغة قوانغدونغ
She's grown up. Don't worry about her.
لقد كبرت أنت تهتم كثيرا
Go to sleep.
نامي
I've never thought about what you said before.
لم أفكر في ما قلته
Take your time to think about it.
لا تستعجلي فكري ببطء
What's wrong?
ماذا تفعل
I want to show you something.
أريد أن أريك شيئاً
What's it?
ماذا؟
That day, I somehow went the wrong way
في ذلك اليوم لا أعرف لماذا أخطأت في الطريق
and got to the lane leading to Fairy Cove.
‫وصلنا إلى طريق خليج الجنية
Fairy Cove is a very important place to me.
خليج الجنية هو مكان مهم بالنسبة لي
I thought since I was already there,
لقد جئت
I should take something as a souvenir.
سأحتفظ بالذكرى
So I pried out the bullets Sulitan used to kill wolves
استخدم السكين لإطلاق الرصاصة
with a knife.
‫من ضرب الذئب‬
On my way back, I met you.
ثم التقيت بك في طريق العودة
That night,
في تلك الليلة
you saved my life.
‫أنقذت اثنين من اليدين الدموية
I was so scared.
سأعزفها مباشرة
Later, I'll drill two holes
عندما يحين الوقت
in them
في ذلك الوقت
so that we can hang them
اربط الحبل
around our necks with strings.
‫سنعلق على رقبتنا
One for each of us
คนละ واحدة
as love tokens, okay?
رمز الحب
Sure.
ممكن
They're just makeshift love tokens.
هذا محل
After I earn money, I'll replace them with jade stones.
بعد العثور على المال سنبدل قطعتين من اليشم
Trust me.
ثقي بي
I'm a man who can earn a lot of money.
أنا بالتأكيد رجل يمكنه كسب المال
After I earn a lot of money,
عندما أجد المال
I'll put it in a separate bank card for you.
سأحفظ لك بطاقة خاصة
Then you'll sew a pocket
‫ثم أنت في بنطالك‬
into your pants,
في سروالك
and I'll stitch it up for you.
سأغلقه لك
Do you want black wood ears?
هل تريد إذن الأسود؟
So many of them.
هذا كثير
Okay. I'll give you one yuan.
حسنا سأعطيك يوان
Plus two pieces of candy.
أضف قطعتين من السكر
I'll give you one more.
سأعطيك واحدة أخرى
Thank you.
شكرا
-Thank you. -Let's go.
شكرا لنذهب
Sir, have you seen this before?
أخي هل رأيت هذا من قبل؟
Black wood ears.
إذن الأسود
Kara.
بولا
Kara, black.
‫سوداء‬
Kara. Kara mushrooms.
الفطر
What is a mushroom?
ما هو الفطر
Sir, do you want to buy something?
‫أخي هل تريد شراء شيء‬
I need that.
هذا
Kara mushrooms.
الفطر
Wait a moment.
انتظر لحظة
Thank you.
شكرا
Take it.
خذها
No.
لا
Where did you find those kara mushrooms?
من أين حفرت هذا الفطر
Over there. There are a lot of them.
هناك الكثير
Where?
إلى أين؟
Over there.
هناك
8 kg of wood ears
ثماني كيلوغرامات رطبة
become only 1 kg after being dried.
يمكن أن تجف كيلوغرام واحد فقط
What are you looking for?
ماذا تبحث
Grandma's green pendant is missing.
‫لقد اختفى القلادة الأخضر
It's just glass. She'll forget it in a few days.
لقد نسيت الزجاجة بعد يومين
Have you really sent Gao Xiaoliang to do deliveries for you?
هل طلبت من "غاو شياو ليانغ" توصيل البضائع لك؟
Can you do it instead?
ما رأيك أن تذهب؟
Sure. I'm good at riding horses now.
حسنًا، أنا بخير في ركوب الخيل الآن
The whole journey takes days,
لقد مرت عدة أيام
and you have to eat and sleep in the open.
وتنام في الخارج
Mom, I need to tell you something.
أمي أريد أن أخبرك بشيء
When I worked in Ürümqi,
عندما كنت أعمل في وولو موتشي
I got fired.
تم طردي
The severance pay was 300 yuan.
دفعت ثلاثمائة رسوم الطرد
Gao Xiaoliang only gave me 100 yuan.
أعطاني جاو شياو ليانغ مائة فقط
What are you trying to say?
ماذا تريد أن تقول؟
He kept 200 yuan to himself.
لقد خدعني 200 يوان
He asked the manager for 300 yuan.
‫وذهب إلى المدير لطلب ثلاثمائة يوان‬
I heard it outside the door.
لقد سمعت كل شيء عند الباب
If he hadn't asked the manager for the money,
إذا لم يطلب المال من المدير
you wouldn't have gotten that 100 yuan.
لن تحصل على مائة يوان
Anyway, he's not a good guy.
على أي حال هو ليس شخصًا جيدًا
Maybe he's not a bag guy either,
ربما ليس سيئا
but he's definitely not a good guy.
لكنه ليس رجلاً جيداً
Listen, Wenxiu.
اسمعي يا ون شيو
You were too thin-skinned to ask for the money.
.أنت خجول، أنا آسفة على التحدث
Gao Xiaoliang did it for you.
"غاو شياو ليانغ" طلب منك المال
So he deserved a cut.
إن لم يكن لديك إنجازات
If you're right,
كما تقول
agencies should all close down.
لا تفتح الوكيل
They take a cut of every deal.
كلنا نحصل على مكافأة
It's the same for my store.
أنا أيضًا
I buy low and sell high.
بيع بسعر منخفض
In your opinion,
حسب كلامك
am I not a good person either?
أنا لست شخصًا جيدًا
It's just business.
العمل
We all need to make a living.
لكسب بعض الطعام
Don't be so serious.
فكر في الأمر
Just keep letting him do deliveries for you.
دعه يرسل لك
Maybe he'll run away with your goods one day.
ربما قام بخداع بضاعتك
The black soap is five yuan each.
هذا الصابون الأسود 5 يوان
The wood ears are 80 yuan per kilo.
80 كيلو يوان
What's so valuable he can cheat me out of
كيف يمكنني خداعه
that it's worth him staying undercover here for a month,
يستحق أن يعمل هنا لمدة شهر
sleeping in that shabby tent?
ينام في تلك الخيمة المكسورة
Mom.
أمي
You've changed.
لقد تغيرت
You're different now.
أنت مختلف عن السابق
I'm already in my forties.
‫أنت أكثر من أربعين عاما‬
There's not much room for me to grow.
إن مساحة النمو محدودة بالفعل
My green gem is gone.
لقد اختفى حجري الأخضر
I need to find another green gem.
سأذهب لجمع حجر أخضر
Wenxiu.
ون شيو
My green gem is gone.
لقد اختفى حجر الخضراء
Go and find a green gem with her.
‫اذهب لترافقها في التقاط اليشم الأخضر‬
And wash those clothes.
وأغسل هذا الفستان
They're at the door.
وضعها عند الباب
Wenxiu.
"ون سيو".
Let's go find another one.
هيا لنلتقط واحدة أخرى
Let's go looking for a green gem.
‫لنلتقط الحجر الأخضر
Wenxiu.
ون شيوه
Chaoge.
الأخ تشاو جي
Where is the man your mother brought back?
أين الرجل الذي أحضرته أمك؟
He's out gathering wood ears.
ذهب لحفر الأذن الخشبية
Where's your mom?
أين والدتك؟
Over there, behind the tent.
هناك خلف الخيمة
Zhang Fengxia.
تشانغ فنغ شيا
Hello.
مرحبا
I need to tell you something.
أريد أن أقول شيئًا
Look.
انظر
I saw it when I was patrolling.
رأيت ذلك عندما كنت أدرس
Someone dug holes in the grass.
‫قام شخص بفتح هذه العشبة‬
So despicable.
‫ما هذا الشخص‬
It's horrible.
ماذا تفعل
Look.
انظر
Look at this. Look.
انظر انظر انظر
Smell it.
شمها
It's the caterpillar fungus.
إنه حشرات
Winter worm, summer grass?
دونغ تشونغ شيا تشاو
No.
لا
This is Xinjiang's caterpillar fungus.
هذا هو الحشرات في شينجيانغ
Look.
انظر
It's different from the caterpillar fungus
إنه مختلف
found in Tibet.
في المخزن الغربي
It doesn't have a stroma.
لا يوجد برج الأرج على هذا
And its medical value
كما أن قيمة هذا الدواء
is not that high.
ليست عالية
But the rest looks exactly the same.
لكن الأخريات متشابهة تماما
So some unscrupulous people
لذلك بعض الناس سيئون للغاية
pass off this caterpillar fungus
استخدم هذه الحشرات
as that found in Tibet.
وتتظاهر بأنه دونغ تشونغ شيا 초
So these little holes
هذا المكان
were left by people who were looking for
من أجل البحث عن دونغ تشونغ شيا 초
the caterpillar fungus?
من أجل البحث عنها؟
They made this mess?
‫جعل هذا المكان هكذا‬
Yes.
هذا صحيح
I saw it while patrolling
رأيتها أثناء الدورية
and was shocked.
لقد أخفتني
Let me tell you.
أقول لك
At this place,
نحن هنا
cattle and sheep mean everything to the herders.
البقر والخروف هو كل شيء للناس
The grass
هذه العشب
means everything to cattle and sheep.
هو كل شيء عن البقر والخروف
Look. We cherish this pasture very much.
انظر نحن نحب هذه العشبة
The herders will definitely be angry if they find out.
لا بد أن الرفاق غاضبون عندما يعرفون
Who did this?
من فعل هذا
Zhang Fengxia.
تشانغ فنغ شيا
You
ماذا عنك؟
are an old friend of the village chief.
أنت صديق قديم مع مدير القرية
You're my friend as well.
إنه صديقي
We trust you without any doubt.
نحن بالتأكيد نثق بك
But the man you brought back
لكن الرجل الذي أحضرته
has been collecting wood ears around this ranch.
كان يقطع الأذن الخشبية في هذا المزرعة
Gao Xiaoliang? It can't be him.
"غاو شياو ليانغ"، لا يمكن أن يكون هو
It can't be Gao Xiaoliang.
لا يمكن أن يكون "غاو شياو ليانغ"
He's just here collecting wood ears.
إنه هنا لتقطع الأذن الخشبية
You know wood ears. They'll grow back next year.
‫إن قطع الأذن الخشبية هذه السنة ستصبح أطول في السنة القادمة
Right?
أليس كذلك
Gosh.
لا
Have you seen him?
هل رأيته؟
Have you been with him?
هل تراه؟
Does he only collect wood ears?
هل يقطع الأذن الخشبية فقط؟
Have you seen him dig for the caterpillar fungus?
هل شاهدته يحفر دونغ تشونغ شيا 초؟
It just can't be him.
قلت أنه لا يمكن أن يكون هو
He's from the city.
إنه من المدينة
He's a city guy.
إنه رجل في المدينة
He doesn't even know how to dig for the caterpillar fungus.
لا يعرف كيف يحفر دونغ تشونغ شيا 초
How could it be him?
كيف نحفر
He's just here collecting wood ears.
إنه هنا فقط لتقطع الأذن الخشبية
You don't understand.
لا أفهم
Look at the grass.
انظر إلى أرضنا
There are holes everywhere!
في هذه المراعي
Goodbye, Zhang Fengxia.
تشانغ فنغ شيا مع السلامة
See you, Chief.
وداعاً، سيد القرية
Did you bring mosquito repellent with you?
هل أحضرت هذا الزيت؟
No.
لا
I almost got eaten alive by mosquitoes.
لقد عضني البعوض
Turpan has great grapes. Hami has sweet melons.
‫قيأ عنب لو فان  البطيخ السري
The Haba River has a lot of mosquitoes.
‫أمسك البعوض في نهر هابا‬
A lot of mosquitoes.
قبض على واحد
It's not funny at all.
أنت تمزح
Look at your hands.
انظر إلى يدك
They're covered with red bumps.
مليئة بالمالظرف الأحمر
Why did they come to you?
لماذا يبحثون عنك؟
For something in the county.
للتحدث عن شؤون البلدة
Listen. The packaging.
دعني أخبرك، هل تتظاهر؟
Don't do packaging like that.
لا تتظاهر هكذا
The roads are bumpy.
‫أنت متعب طوال الطريق‬
They'll break
كلها مكسورة
and become less valuable.
لا يمكن بيعها
I don't have polystyrene foam.
‫ليس لدي فلاش الفقاعات‬
You don't have polystyrene foam,
ليس لديك فلاش الفقاعات
but you have dried grass here.
أليس هناك عشب جاف هنا
I got dried grass for you
لقد صنعت لك هذا العشب الجاف
in this box.
هنا
Lay it on the bottom.
ضعها في أسفل الغرفة
Okay.
حسنا
Don't…
لا
Can't you be gentler?
.تعيش حياة أسوأ مني
Let's go, Gao Xiaoliang. Leave them here.
هيا يا "غاو شياو ليانغ"، توقف
Where are we going?
إلى أين؟
Let's go drink by the river.
لنشرب الخمر بجانب النهر
I haven't finished this.
لم أنتهي من أخذ هذا
I've had beers chilling in the river.
لقد تجمدت بيرة باردة في النهر
I need to get it done first.
‫لا يوجد حل بعد الجليد‬
They need to be dried again.
قومي بتشغيل هذا مرة أخرى
Let's go.
هيا بنا
There's a rainbow by the river.
هناك قوس قزح بجانب النهر
What should I do with you?
يا لك من وقح
We can go after finishing the work.
ما رأيك أن ننتهي أولا ثم نذهب
No.
لا
Is this horse dung?
‫phân الحصان‬
It's sheep dung.
phân الخروف
She drank again?
لقد شربت مرة أخرى
They're nice boots.
حذاء جميل
I waded into the water and completely ruined them.
‫لقد دست على الماء وانهيت كل شيء‬
These are designer shoes.
هذا زوج من العلامة التجارية
I'm thinking that
أفكر اليوم
you don't have to go to the county seat.
في الواقع لا داعي للذهاب إلى البلدة
Eid al-Adha is coming next month.
.الشهر المقبل هو عيد غول بانغ
There will be many horse race meetings
سيكون هناك العديد من المنافسة
and concerts.
الحفل الغنائي
You can bring them there
يمكنك في ذلك الوقت
and sell them then.
في ذلك الوقت
You don't have to go to the county seat.
لا داعي للذهاب إلى البلدة
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
You don't want me to go now?
ألا تريدني أن أذهب الآن
I'll stay there for a few days and sell goods,
بيع البضائع سأسكن هناك لبضعة أيام
finding a bed to sleep on
سأنام على السرير ليومين
to make my lower back feel better.
خصري لا يتحمل
I'll be back before the festival.
سأعود قبل عيد الميلاد
Okay?
حسنا
Give me your answer when I come back.
أعطني إجابة قبل عودتك
I'm leaving.
سأذهب
Whether you come back or not,
لا يهم إذا عدت أم لا
don't hang out with those who sell
لا تكن مع أولئك الذين يبيعون الحشرات المزيفة
the fake caterpillar fungus.
مع هؤلاء
Make money in an honorable way.
الرجل النبيل يحب المال
What's wrong with you?
هل أنت مجنون
You're thinking too much.
أفكر كثيرا
Go back. It's cold outside.
عودي بسرعة الجو بارد
Be good. Go back.
كن مطيعا بسرعة
Dried wood ears from a summer ranch.
خشب مجفف مزرعة شيا
Sir, do you want dried wood ears from a summer ranch?
‫أيها الرئيس هل تريد شراء الأذن المجفف في مزرعة شيا‬
No, no.
لا لا
They're delicious and crunchy.
لذيذ حلوة
Sir.
يا صديقي
Would you like some dried wood ears from a summer ranch?
هل تريد أن تأخذ بعض الخشب المجفف في مزرعة شيا؟
No, no, no.
لا لا لا
Dried wood ears from a summer ranch.
مزرعة شيا   مزرعة شيا
Crunchy dried wood ears.
‫شفاه مقرمشة ورقة‬
No, no.
لا لا لا
No.
لا لا
80 is too expensive?
80 لا
Not interested.
لا
I'll give you a discount. How about 70?
سأعطيك المزيد سأعطيك 70
I sell fruits. I don't want that.
أنا أبيع الفاكهة لا أريد ذلك
You can eat them yourself.
بيع الفاكهة خذها إلى المنزل
No, no, no.
لا لا لا
They're good for your lungs.
هذا جيد لرئتك
You smoke. They're good for your lungs, you know?
أنت تدخن ، أنت جيد لرئتك ، هل تعرف؟
They're from a summer ranch.
مزرعة شيا
Who knows if you're lying.
مزرعة شيا من يعرف
I can soak some in water for you.
سأحضر الماء لك
-Then you'll know. -No, no, no.
‫انظر هل تريد أم لا لا لا لا
Go away. I don't have time for that. Go.
هيا بنا، ليس لدينا وقت، هيا بنا
You want black herbal soaps, right?
هل أنتم هنا تلتقطون الصابون الأسود
This is an embroidery shop. We don't sell anything else.
نحن في متجر التطريز، لا نبيع أي شيء آخر
5-1, 45.
خمسة رصاص واحد أربعة وأربعون
The shop owner is a woman. It should be here.
‫هذا صحيح يا سيدة
Did you ask Zhang Fengxia to buy black herbal soaps for you?
هل طلبت من تشانغ فنغ شيا أخذ الصابون الأسود
Zhang Fengxia sent you here? You should've said so.
تشانغ فنغ شيا طلب منك المجيء   لماذا لم تخبرني مبكرا
Count them.
اطلب
100 pieces.
مائة
Four, six.
أربعة ستة
Is there anyone nearby who will buy wood ears?
‫هل يوجد أي من يجمع الأذن الخشبية بالقرب من هنا‬
Go straight. There's another market ahead.
‫اذهب للأمام هناك سوق آخر‬
Okay. Thank you.
شكرا
Hey, bro, what do you need?
تعال يا أخي ماذا تريد أن ترى
I have dried wild wood ears. Are you interested?
‫البرية جافة  هل ستأخذها أم لا
How much?
كيف تبيع
100 yuan per kilo.
مائة
Too expensive. These are only 40 yuan per kilo.
إنه غالي جداً أنا فقط أبيع أربعون يوان
Take a look at mine first.
ألق نظرة على بضاعتي
These are farmed. They don't taste good.
طعمك غير جيد في تربية النباتات
How about 40?
هل تبيع أربعون
Take a look. Compare them.
ألق نظرة
No, no, no.
لا لا لا لا
Do you know Zhang Fengxia?
هل تعرف تشانغ فنغ شيا
Why?
ماذا
These are her wood ears.
هذه البضائع لها
Does Zhang Fengxia sell wood ears?
هل يبيع تشانغ فنغ شيا mộc أر
We live on a ranch in Naren,
نحن في ذلك المزرعة
running a store.
بيع الأشياء
I went into the pine forest
ذهبت إلى سونغلين
and cut these wood ears one by one.
سأقطع واحدة تلو الأخرى
Zhang Fengxia's wood ears?
بضائع تشانغ فنغ شيا
Let me take a look.
دعني أرى
Take a look.
انظر
We just dried them.
لقد جف مجموعة من البضائع للتو
They're very crunchy.
طعمه رقيق للغاية
They'll definitely sell better than yours.
‫من المؤكد أن البيع أفضل من ذلك‬
Trust me. I'm sure of it.
أقول لك لا أكذب عليك
Not bad.
حسنا
How many do you have?
كم عدد البضائع
How's the sale of wood ears going?
كيف بيع آر الخشب
Not bad.
لا بأس به
How much are they?
كيف تبيع
100 yuan per kilo.
مائة
I've been out for many days.
لقد خرجت منذ عدة أيام
If you're interested, I can give you a discount.
هل أنت مهتم يمكنني أن أرخص قليلا
How about 80?
80 يوان
You collected them on a summer ranch?
هل تم قطعه من مزرعة شيا
Which summer ranch?
أي مزرعة شيا
One in Naren,
هناك
near the Altay Mountains.
أوشكنا على الوصول إلى آر تايشان
High altitude.
‫ارتفاع البحر العالي‬
That's why they're crunchy.
لذلك رقيق
They taste great.
إنه لذيذ، إنه لذيذ
Do you know this?
هل تعرف هذا؟
What's that?
ما هذا؟
Caterpillar fungus. You can find it in Naren.
الحشرات هناك
I've never seen it before.
لم أره من قبل
If you can get this,
إذا استطعت الحصول على هذا في المستقبل
I'll buy as many as you have.
أريد كل ما لديك
You don't want wood ears? They're really crunchy.
‫هل لا تريد آذن الخشب رقيق جدا‬
If you buy all of them,
خذها كلها
I can give you a bigger discount.
سأعطيك خصمًا أكثر
They're worthless.
لا قيمة لها
How much will you pay for caterpillar fungi?
كم تريد
10,000 yuan per kilo.
كيلوغرام عشرة آلاف يوان
Let's talk.
لنتحدث
Darn it.
تبا لك
Jangber.
جيانغ بو إر
Zhang Fengxia.
تشانغ فنغ شيا
Happy Eid Day.
عيد جو إر بانغ سعيد
Well, I'm here to settle the bill.
تعال سأدفع لك
Here's your money. Take it.
خذ أموالك
For kara soaps.
صابون
Black herbal soaps?
الصابون الأسود
Where did you get the money?
من أين حصلت على المال؟
Didn't your man run away with your goods?
أليس زوجك هرب مع البضائع
Yeah. This is your money. Take it.
‫نعم  نقودك  خذ جيدا
Take it.
خذها جيدا
Zhang Fengxia, don't pretend that you can't understand me.
تشانغ فنغ شيا لا تتظاهر بأنك لا تفهم
You were cheated by that man. Just keep the money.
لقد تم خداعك من قبل الرجال، أعطني المال
I don't want it.
لا أريد
Yeah, yeah.
هذا صحيح
There's a horse race meeting today.
مسابقة الخيول اليوم
I'll make a lot of money.
.سأجني الكثير منه
Don't worry about me.
لا تقلقي بشأني
Take your money. Don't worry.
خذ أموالك اطمئن
Zhang Fengxia.
تشانغ فنغ شيا
I heard that your man ran away.
سمعت أن زوجك قد هرب
Chief, why is there pity in your voice?
سيد القرية، ما الذي تتحدثين عنه؟
That man ran away.
لقد هرب رجل
So what?
ما الرائع في ذلك
We outsiders
نحن الغرباء
are different from you locals.
مختلف عن السكان المحليين
It's not embarrassing for us to get divorced.
لن نخجل بعد الطلاق
I can just find another man.
ابحث عن رجل آخر
Am I right, Jangber?
أليس كذلك جيانغ بو إر
I'm leaving.
سأذهب
She's the last woman
النساء في العالم
you need to worry about in the world.
لا داعي للقلق أكثر هي